僕は悪くない。僕は悪くない。僕は悪くない。パソコンが悪い。
パスワードがうまくいかないみたいよ。
ラジオ英会話、アートでつかめ。英語の極意、講師の尾西、ひろとです。
Hey everyone, Akina Rosa here.
And I'm David Evans.
Yeah, he's always forgetting his password.
それでは、さっそく始めていきましょう。
Lesson 108
動詞句、修飾、その3。動詞ING系で説明。
今日のキーセンテンスはこちら。
動詞句の修飾。今回は動詞ing形を置いてみましょう。
英語はね、後ろにポンポンと並べていけば説明となる簡単なシステムの言葉なんです。
それでは今日のダイアログから確認しましょう。
同じ職場で働くジョナスとイヤヨイが会社で話しています。
新しいタブレットが支給されたようですね。
Hey, Yayoi, have you set up your new tablet?
Yes, I did it yesterday. Are you having problems?
Yeah, can you give me a hand?
Sure. First, you need to enter your password using the keypad.
I tried that, but it didn't work.
I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
Take it easy. Did you type it in right?
Try again. It's the password on this slip of paper, right?
Yes, and it's case sensitive.
It worked!
Okay, next step.
Hey, Yayoi, have you set up your new tablet?
やあ、弥生。新しいタブレットの設定は終わりましたか?
Yes, I did it yesterday. Are you having problems?
ええ、昨日のうちに済ませました。あなたは何か問題があるんですか?
Yeah, can you give me a hand?
そうなんです。ちょっと手伝ってくれますか?
Sure. First you need to enter your password using the keypad.
いいですよ。
まずキーパッドを使ってパスワードを入力する必要があります。
I tried that, but it didn't work.
I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
それはやってみましたが、うまくいかなかったんです。
午前中ずっとその設定だけに時間を取られたくありません。
The didn't work. うまくいかなかった。
まとめて覚えておくと、使い出がある表現ですよ。
Take it easy. Did you type it in right?
Try again.
落ち着いてね。正しく入力しましたか?もう一度やってみてください。
さあ、Take it easy. 落ち着いて、気軽に。
まあ、そうしたフレーズですよね。目的語説明型です。
Itイコールイーズイなものとして受け取れというわけですね。
そして、Type it in. Write.
このRightはType it inの後ろに並んでいます。
Type it inの説明となるわけですね。
It's the password on this slip of paper, right?
この紙に書いてあるのがパスワードですよね。
さあ、スリップという表現を覚えてください。
スリップオブペーパーというふうな使い方をしますが、
細長い小さな紙のことを示します。
Yes, and it's case sensitive.
そう、それから大文字と小文字は区別する必要がありますよ。
Sensitiveという単語。
これは影響を受ける、あるいは敏感な、そうした単語ですよね。
そしてケースというのは、アッパーケース、大文字、ローアーケース、小文字というですね、大文字小文字の別を表しています。
つまり、大文字小文字の区別が重要なというわけです。
It worked! Okay, next step.
うまくいった。さて、次にすることは?
Grammar and Vocabulary
文法と語彙のポイントを確認しましょう。
まず確認するのはジョナスの最初のセリフから。
Have you set up your new tablet?
あなたは新しいタブレットを設定しましたか?
この文のset upはパソコンなどを設定する。
様々な要素を正しくセットして問題なく動くようにしっかりと立ち上がらせるということ。
By the way, this phrase can be used to set up meetings, or to set up an organization, or something like that.
The same is true for this one.
セラペンミーティング 会を設ける is used to set up meetings, or to set up meetings.
Now, let's check out one more of Jonas' lines.
Can you give me a hand?
Can you help me a little?
This sentence is a demand type with two purposes behind the verb.
It means to always give something to someone, no matter what kind of verb you use.
This sentence is an expression that expresses the meaning of giving me a little help.
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
Hey, Yayoi, have you set up your new tablet?
Yes, I did it yesterday. Are you having problems?
Yeah, can you give me a hand?
Sure. First, you need to enter your password using the keypad.
I tried that, but it didn't work. I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
Take it easy. Did you type it in right? Try again.
It's the password on this slip of paper, right?
Yes.
And it's case-sensitive.
It worked!
Okay, next step.
Target forms.
会話に役立つ典型表現を身につけましょう。
まずは今日のキーセンテンスを改めて確認します。
You need to enter your password using the keypad.
あなたはキーパッドを使ってパスワードを入力する必要があります。
動詞句、enter your passwordの後ろにusing the keypad。
もちろん説明ルール、説明は後ろに置くにより、
何をしながらenter your passwordするのか、その説明になっています。
英語は気楽な言葉。
せつめいしたければ、うしろにならべていけばいいだけですよ。
それではさっそくキーセンテンスのれんしゅうをはじめていきましょう。
Practice
さあ、Enter your password そのせつめいということをいしきしながら
Using the keypad これをつづけていきます。
それではわたしのあとにつづけてれんしゅうしましょう。
Enter your password
Enter your password using the keypad
OKですね。さあ、それではフルセンテンスいきます。
You need to enter your password using the keypad.
はい、OKです。それでは、他の例も一緒に身につけていきましょう。
I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
午前中ずっとその設定に時間を費やしたくはありません。
ダイアログの文、spend all morningの説明がsetting it up、それを設定しながら。
私は夕食を料理しながら忙しくしていました。
私はテレビを見ながら遅くまで起きていました。
Stayed up late の内容説明が watching TV。
それでは今紹介した表現をデイビッドさんローザさんと一緒に声に出して練習しましょう。
All right, everyone. It's practice time.
Keeping with our recent theme, let's continue to put the explanation after.
So, doshiku plus explanation. Got it? Here we go.
All right, everyone. Repeat after us.
Spend all morning.
Spend all morning setting it up.
I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
great work let's keep going was busy
was busy
cooking dinner I was busy cooking dinner
and one more
stayed up late stayed up late
watching TV I stayed up late watching TV
Unlock your potential.
Repetition is the key.
Great work.
Grammar in action.
動詞句の後ろに説明を並べて文を作りましょう。
まずはこちら。
彼女は彼女の芸術作品を手を使って作り出します。
彼女はブラシや他の道具を使いません。
ザ芸術作品これはただアートとおっしゃっていただければOKです 彼女は彼女の芸術作品を手を使って作り出します 彼女はブラシや他の道具を使いません
私たちのおすすめは?
She creates her art using her hands.
She doesn't use brushes or other tools.
では音読練習です。
She creates her art using her hands.
She doesn't use brushes or other tools.
So, the next question.
I wasted two days trying to fix my car.
Finally, I took it to the store.
Now, please use the verb to waste.
I wasted two days trying to fix my car.
Finally, I took it to the store.
私たちのおすすめは?
I wasted two days trying to fix my car.
In the end, I took it to a shop.
wasted two days の内容をtrying 以下で説明
try to は何々しようと試みる 頑張る
では音読練習です。
I wasted two days trying to fix my car.
In the end, I took it to a shop.
Soredewa mou ichimon.
Watashitachi wa oshaberi shitari,
nondari shite tanoshiku sugoshimashita.
Hontou ni tanoshii ban deshita.
Korewa no hinto dekimashou.
Watashitachi wa
We had a great time talking and drinking.
It was a really fun evening.
We had a great time talking and drinking. It was a really fun evening.
Had a great time. 楽しんだの内容をtalking and drinkingが説明。
英語は並べていくだけの言葉。難しくはありませんよ。
では音読練習です。
We had a great time talking and drinking. It was a really fun evening.
Boku wa warukunai. Boku wa warukunai. Boku wa warukunai.
Aw, is the big bad computer still being mean to you?
Oh, yes.
Sensei, that's not even your computer.
Dakara ka?
Soudatta ka.
Toiwakeda, kyou wa konohende.
Bye!